&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Thank you so much
for helping me get to the
Keynote.  I can't thank you
enough.
&gt;&gt; Listen.  The least I can
do.  What are you going to talk
about?  Is there any insider
information you can give me?
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: We are going to
talk about some great stuff.
&gt;&gt; Right.  That just sounds
like a press release.  Is this
true?  I have read that the
security on the new iPhone is
going to be the best of its
kind.
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Absolutely.
&gt;&gt; Do you know how I read t
that?
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: How?
&gt;&gt; A leak on the Internet.  Do
you see the irony of that?
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: I do see the
irony of that.
&gt;&gt; Who is your favorite band?
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: I love
(Singing)
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: Siri, what do
you think of Tim Cook?
&gt;&gt; SIRI: He's wonderful, but
scheduling his appointments is
crazy.
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: Siri, what do
you think of James Corden?
&gt;&gt; SIRI: This is about you,
not me.
(Laughter)
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: What are you
going to wear for the launch?
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: I was planning on
just wearing what I've got on
here.
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: This is a big
deal.
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: I know.
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: If I was you,
I would be like wearing a suit
made entirely of apples or
maybe a cane with an Apple logo
on the top, shades.  You walk
on and go, this is it, bitches.
Get in line.
(Laughter)
Hang on.  I know someone who
knows a thing or two about
fashion.  Hang on.
&gt;&gt; PHARRELL WILLAMS: Hey, g
guys.
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: That was
quick.
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Great to see you.
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: You've got
some shades.  That's what I am
saying.
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: What do you th
think?
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: Already you
are changing up Apple every
single day.  I think we should
listen to some music and we
should listen to a song all
about where you are from.
(Singing)
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: All right.
Here we are.  Have a great one.
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Thanks, James.
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: Remember
everything I said, confidence,
a couple of jokes, get out of
there.
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Thanks for these.
&gt;&gt; JAMES CORDEN: I am rooting
for you.  Here we go.  Tim C
Cook, ladies and gentlemen.
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Good morning!
Good morning!  Thank you.
Thank you.  Thank you.  Good
morning!  Good morning.  Thank
you for joining us, and welcome
to San Francisco.  I am so glad
James got me here on time.  And
it was so much fun seeing he
and Pharrell, I may have lost
my voice.
As you may know, we are
working with Carpool Karaoke on
some new episodes that will be
premiering on Apple Music early
next year, so check them out.
I can guarantee you everybody
singing will have a voice much
better than mine.
We've got some great things to
share with you this morning,
and I'd like to get started
with a few updates.  Beginning
with Apple Music.  As you know,
we've always had a deep love
for music.  It inspires us, and
it's such a gee part of our
product experience.  Since
launch, Apple Music has grown
to over 17 million subscribers.
(Applause)
Thank you.
Our users love having access
to over 30 million songs and
personal recommendations from
people who really know and love
music.
There's a great new simple and
intuitive design in iOS 10 that
makes it so easy to listen to
your favorite songs and
discover new music, and Apple
Music has content that no one
else has.  Apple Music has
become the premiere destination
for new artists and existing
artists to launch their
inclusive music.  This past
year alone, Apple Music was the
first place to hear over 70
great releases from such stars
as Taylor Swift, Blake Shelton,
Drake, Frank Ocean, and so many
more.
(Applause)
Thank you.  One of our most
pop popular inclusives of all
is the Apple Music festival in
London, and it begins just
three days from now.  This
great event has become a great
tradition that our customers
look forward to every year.
This year we are celebrating
the tenth anniversary of the
Apple Music festival, and we
have an amazing lineup.  This
year includes Elton John,
OneRepublic, Britney Spears,
and so many more artists.  It's
going to be amazing.  If you
can't make it to London, you
can join the millions that will
be watching it for free on the
live stream from your Apple
devices, including your Apple
TV.
That's a brief update on Apple
Music.  It just keeps getting
better.
(Applause)
Now I'd like to talk about the
App Store.  Apps continue to do
more and more amazing things,
from allowing you to rent that
spare bedroom to contributing
to advanced medical research.
The App Store has forever
changed the world of software
and forever changed all of our
lives, and the momentum for
apps in the App Store have
never been greater.  Over 140
billion apps have now been
downloaded from the App Store.
(Applause)
This is phenomenal.  And
what's even more phenomenal is
we continue to set new records,
and the growth is literally off
the charts.  In fact, in the
last two months, we've seen
growth rates of over 100% year
on year.  This is unbelievable.
It's pretty clear from this
that our users' love affair
with apps for their iPhone and
iPad is as strong as ever.
Now, the most recent quarter
the App Store generated twice
the global revenue of our n
nearest competitor.  This is
really great for developers,
and it's why that so many
developers develop first on iOS
and many only on iOS.  And
this, of course, is great for
our users.  The combination of
our incredible products and the
success of the App Store has
made the iPhone and the iPad
the most popular gaming devices
in the world.  And gaming is
the biggest and most popular
category on the Store, with
over a half a million games to
choose from.
But there's been something --
or rather someone -- missing,
and I am so happy to announce
today he is coming to the App
Store.
(Cheers and applause)
Welcome, Mario!  And please
welcome from Nintendo the
father of Mario, Shigeru
Miyamoto.
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; SHIGERU MIYAMOTO: Hello.
Good morning, everyone.  Thank
you, Tim.
For the past 30 years, every
time Mario has encountered a
new platform, he has evolved
and continued running towards a
new goal.  And now, Mario is
running towards his next goal,
iPhone.
(Applause)
Please let me speak in
Japanese, so I would like to
ask Bill Trinen to translate.
We want as many people as
possible all around the world
to be able to enjoy playing as
Mario, and they will be doing
it first on iOS.  And they will
be doing it in a brand-new g
game, Super Mario Run.
The magic of Mario is that
anyone can pick up a game and
instantly start playing, and
this time we've made it even
simpler to begin.  So, why
don't we show you how.  Now, as
the title suggests, Mario runs
automatically to the right.
And as he does, he will hurdle
small gaps and certain enemies.
It's very simple, and the
movement feels great.  With
just the tap of a finger a
anywhere on the touchscreen,
you can make Mario jump, and
the longer you tap, the higher
he jumps.  This is key to
getting high scores.  In later
levels, you will see blocks
that will change Mario's
direction and others that will
start and stop him with
precision timing.  But the goal
remains simple:  Collect as
many coins as you can and get
to the flagpole at the end of
the level before time runs out.
But what's new this time,
what's different, is that you
can play the game one-handed
for the very first time.  What
that means is that you can play
while holding on to a handle on
the subway.
(Laughter)
While eating a hamburger.
Or while eating an apple.
(Laughter)
(Applause)
But in addition to the
traditional Mario gameplay,
we've also prepared a brand-new
way to play.  It's a new battle
mode called Toad Rally.  And
the first thing that you do in
battle mode is you choose an
opponent from this list to try
to beat their high score.
Today I've ask Hideki to play
for me, so who should he
compete against?  Looks like he
picked Phil.  So we are going
to try to beat Phil's high
score.
Now, battle mode will have you
competing not only against your
friends, but for the first t
time, players around the world.
The victory in battle mode is
determined based on the number
of coins you collect and the
number of toads you impress,
because the toad characters
appear every time you do a
daring move.  There's no
flagpole in the battle mode, so
you just keep running, jumping,
and collecting coins until time
runs out.  As you do, you may
see a little sticker of Mario
moving through the course.  In
this case, that shows us what
Phil was doing on his run,
where he collected his coins,
and where he gathered his toad
fans.
In the matches that you win,
the toads you gather will
become residents of your very
own mushroom kingdom.  So
another new element you can
enjoy is expanding and
customizing your mushroom k
kingdom using the coins you
collect in the game.
Oh, at the end of battle mode,
Toadette appears to tally the
score and show who won.  Good
job!
(Applause)
Sorry, sorry, Phil.
We want as many people of all
ages to be able to enjoy
playing Super Mario Run.  For
that reason, we plan on
releasing the game at a set
price, so you won't have to
worry about continuing to pay.
You will just be able to play
to your heart's content.
(Applause)
We'll announce pricing later,
but Super Mario Run will
release in time for holidays in
2016.  I hope you look forward
to it.
(Applause)
We have one more piece of news.
We've prepared a set of Super
Mario sickers for iMessage that
will launch day and date with
iOS 10 that I hope you will
send to all your friends and
family.  In the meantime, you
can look forward to Super Mario
Run.  Thank you very much.
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Thank you.  Thank
you, Miyamoto-San.  We could
not be more honored that
Nintendo chose to bring Mario
to iOS first.  So that's a
brief update on the App Store.
Now, as we start a new school
year, let's turn our attention
to education.  Apple celebrated
its 40th birthday earlier this
year, and it's no coincidence
that we've been committed to
education for that entire time.
It's simply deep in our DNA.
We've always believed that
education is a great equalizer.
It's a powerful force of
change for good.  And we've
always believed that our
products could have a
tremendous positive impact on
teachers and students.  But we
are keenly aware that not every
school can have this impact.
And that's why we are so deeply
committed to ConnectED.
ConnectED, as you probably k
know, is a national initiative
combining government and
leading technologies to bring
-- leading technology companies
to bring technology to
underserved schools.
I personally visited several
of these ConnectED schools, and
the program is having amazing
results.  Kids are engaged like
never before.  They are
learning like never before.  It
is as it should be.
We are proud this morning to
have some ConnectED teachers
and students join us, and I'd
like you to welcome them from
Santee Elementary in San Jose
and Stege Elementary from
Richmond, California.  Please
join me in welcoming them.
(Applause)
And I am thrilled to tell you
that this fall all 114 schools
that Apple is supporting will
be up and running.  That means
we are giving a Mac and an iPad
to 4500 teachers, an Apple TV
in every classroom, and we are
donating iPads to more than
50,000 students.
(Applause)
Thank you.
Now, the response has been so
inspiring.  Trina Siegfried
from Crane Elementary in Yuma,
Arizona, told us this:  The
kecd Ed grant meant a complete
transformation.  The students
are having fun.  They're more
engaged.  Most importantly, we
are seeing a real love of
learning.  That is as it should
be.  We can't wait to see what
these kids are going to do this
school year, and we are so very
proud to be a part of it.
But we are not stopping there.
We believe every student
should have the opportunity to
code.  So we've created a
program called Everyone Can
Code.  It's Apple's approach to
teaching coding, and it's a
cornerstone of ConnectED.  It
starts with the amazing iPad
app Swift Playgrounds, which we
just announced in June.  And
what this does is it teaches
Swift, our popular programming
language, to all of these kids
in a simple, fun, and
interactive way.
Already, since June, more than
100 schools and school
districts around the world have
already planned to teach Swift
Playgrounds this fall.  It's
unbelievably exciting to us.
(Applause)
We are so excited that they
moved to put this in their
curriculum so, so quickly.
Now, I'd like to talk to you
about one other very important
tool in education, and that is
iWork.  Of course, iWork
provides a suite of
productivity tools which are
very popular in education but
also in business and consumers.
Teachers and students love
creating stunning documents and
presentations and even
spreadsheets.  I'd like to
invite Susan Prescott, our Vice
President of Worldwide Apps
Product Markets to tell you
what's next with iWork.  Susan?
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; SIRI:
&gt;&gt; SUSAN PRESCOTT: Thank you,
Tim.  Thank you.  Pages,
Keynote, and Numbers are built
to take advantage of iOS,
macOS, and of course, our
amazing devices.  And iWork is
all about making beautiful and
engaging documents.  But for
people who want the power of
iWork, there is just not a
great way for them to work with
classmates or colleagues to
create projects together.  But
today I'm very excited to
announce and introduce
real-time collaboration.
(Applause)
In all of the iWork apps, the
exact same apps you use on your
Mac, iPad, and iPhone.  Of
course, we use them too, even
our big presentations like this
one are built using Keynote,
which got me thinking we could
edit slides right here right
now.  We have never edited a
deck live on stage before.  I
think the reasons are obvious.
(Laughter)
But we are so excited to show
you our real-time collab
collaboration, we're going to
do it.
(Cheers and applause)
So we'll start by hitting
Escape to go from play mode
into edit mode so we can add a
couple of slides about
collaboration.  If I go to the
Participants list, I can see my
colleagues I've already invited
to work on the deck with me.
We've got Greg, Lesley,
Michelle, and Rodney.  They
each have a color associated
with them, so when they
actually begin editing, you
will see a colored bubble come
up with their name.  Now, get
ready because we are going to
be adding images, graphics,
text, and even animations all
in real time.
I am going to start by adding
a slide.  Lesley can bring in
an image.  That one looks
perfect.  And Michelle can add
a graphic of an iPad.  That
would be ideal.  That looks
great.  I think you get the
idea.  So let's watch as
everybody gets to work.
Remember, this is happening
live.  And look how super
responsive it is, even with the
beautiful visuals that make
iWork documents stand out.  And
you can work from your Mac,
your iPad, your iPhone, or even
the Web.  It's amazing.
I see in the thumbnails that
Greg's added a new slide, which
is fantastic, and of course, we
are collaborating together, so
I can also edit anything here.
But it looks like we are about
ready, so let's take a look.
You ready?  Wow.  That looks
amazing, and it could only
happen working together.
(Applause)
That is just a very quick look
at real-time collaboration in
iWork.  It will change the way
you work with classmates, with
colleagues, and with friends.
You're gonna love it.  Thank
you so much.
(Applause)
Town
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Thanks, Susan.
So that's a little bit about
education and some things that
are important to us.  I'd now
like to turn to new products
beginning with Apple Watch.
(Applause)
We started shipping Apple
Watch just 18 months ago, and
already people all over the
world are using it in many
aspects of their daily lives.
It's the best way to get
notifications so you don't miss
that urgent phone call or
message.  You can quickly and
conveniently pay for things
with Apple Pay.  And we
couldn't be happier that so
many people are using it to
become more active and healthy.
Apple Watch has really changed
what people expect from a wa
watch.  Before Apple Watch,
these were the top watch brands
in the world as measured by
sales revenue.  This is what
happened after we launched
Apple Watch.
(Cheers and applause)
We became the number two watch
brand in the world, despite
only shipping 8 months of 2015.
We are also the top selling
smartwatch, but as everyone
knows in here, what's really
important to us is that we
delight our customers, and I am
pleased to tell you that
customers love the Apple Watch.
Survey after survey, Apple
Watch tops number one in
customer satisfaction,
including the most recent JD
Power smartwatch study.
Now, so Apple Watch has set a
very high bar about what a
modern watch can be, but we are
just getting started.  And to
tell you about what is next
with Apple Watch, I'd like to
invite Jeff Williams up.  Jeff?
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; JEFF WILLIAMS: Thanks, Tim.
We've got a lot to talk about,
so let's get started.
In June, we previewed watchOS
3, and it is packed with
features.  Your favorite apps
launch instantly with
information already up-to-date
so they are ready when you need
them.  There's a new dock so
you can quickly access your
favorite apps.  And we've made
it easier than ever to switch
watch faces.  You just swipe
edge to edge.  And we've added
some great new faces, like
these activity ones.
Messaging is more expressive
than ever with features like
tap back, where you double-tap
a message to send a quick re
reply.  There are fun animated
stickers.  You've just got to
love Donald Duck.  And you can
enjoy full-screen effects like
confetti to celebrate special
moments.  You can also write
custom replies with Scribble.
And for those of you who are
skeptical, which is probably a
lot of you, about writing on
the small screen, you should
try it.  You will be amazed how
well it works.  And it works in
-- (Applause) -- thank you,
Eddy.  And it works in both
simplified and traditional
Chinese as well.
We've added activity sharing
to the Watch, closing the rings
is already this fun, healthy
obsession, and now you can
share with your friends and
family and encourage them to be
more active.  We have a
brand-new app called Breathe.
Each day it reminds you to take
a moment and do a d
deep-breathing exercise.  It's
a great way to be more mindful
and manage everyday stress.
And we've added a really
important app, it's a safety
feature that allows you to
contact emergency services by
simply pressing and holding the
side button.  Within seconds,
you will be on a call with 911
or the equivalent number in the
country you are in, and in
addition, a message will be
sent to your emergency con
contacts, along with your
location, so they are in a
better position to assist you.
This is something we hope you
never use, but it's really
comforting to know it's there.
(Applause)
In addition to all these great
built-in apps, developers have
been hard at work already on
watchOS 3.  So apps like the
Washington Post and Major
League Soccer, they launch
instantly with information
already up-to-date.  Gaming
apps like Field Day take
advantage of the powerful
graphics tools in watchOS 3,
like SceneKit and SpriteKit.
Fitness apps like Sweat with
Kayla and P90x have access to
real-time heart rate.  And Ping
will use the gyroscope to
analyze and hopefully improve
your golf swing.
So, so many great apps, but
there's one special one that I
am excited to tell you about
today.  Pokemon Go is coming to
the Watch.
(Applause)
And to tell you more about it,
I'd like to invite to the stage
John Hanke, CEO of Niantic L
Labs.
&gt;&gt; JOHN HANKE: Thank you, J
Jeff.
Well, it's certainly been a
busy summer for us at Niantic
and also for our friends at the
Pokemon Company.  I hope many
of you have had a chance to try
Pokemon Go for iPhone.  If you
have, you are not alone.  Since
we launched in early July,
Pokemon Go has been downloaded
more than 500 million times
around the world.
(Applause)
More importantly, Pokemon
trainers collectively have
walked more than 4.6 billion
kilometers while playing the
game.
(Applause)
So, Pokemon Go is about
exploration.  It's also about
having fun outside with your
family or with your friends.
And because of that, we have
been really interested to f
finding ways that enable you to
play while focusing less on
your screen and more on the
stuff around you.  That was the
inspiration for this device,
the Pokemon Go Plus developed
by our partners at Nintendo.
It works with your iPhone to
enable heads-up gameplay for
Pokemon Go, and it will be
available later this month.
This morning, we are really
excited to show you something
new that we've been working on.
It's designed to seamlessly
blend Pokemon Go gameplay with
your daily walk or run while
enabling you to focus on what's
important, all the cool stuff
around you.  Pokemon Go on
Apple Watch.
(Applause)
I want to introduce the
project manager from Pokemon
Go, Tatsuo Nomura, to give you
a demo.
&gt;&gt; TATSUO NOMURA: Thank you,
John.  For Pokemon trainers out
there, sometimes Pokemon can
hatch from the egg by walking
with it.  Good news.  From a
complication on the watch face,
I can see how far I need to
walk to hatch an egg.  The main
screen shows my current level
and XP I need to get to the
next.  My walk is recorded as a
workout because it helps me
make faster progress towards my
activity goals.
All right.  Let's take a walk.
During my walk, I can see how
far I walked and the calories
burned.  At a glance, I see
which Pokemon are nearby.  So
let's keep walking.  A wild
snorlax appeared!
(Applause)
Ah, if it wasn't for this
demo, I definitely would have
taken out my iPhone to catch
it.  Oh, well.  Let's keep
walking.
When I approach a PokeStop, a
tap on my wrist lets me know.
PokeStops are located at
interesting places, such as
public art works and historical
landmarks.  This one is Bill
Graham.  Interesting.  Let's
collect some items.  I just
swipe, sweet, I got an ultra
ball.
With Pokemon Go on Apple Wa
Watch, I will never miss a
PokeStop.
Oh, I think I just earned a
gold medal.  This means I
visited 2,000 PokeStops.
That's pretty impressive.
(Laughter)
I am going to keep walking to
see if I can hatch an egg.  Oh?
Here we are.  Let's see what
hatches.  Yes, it's a Pikachu.
(Applause)
Isn't that exciting?
Now that I've done walking,
let's end my workout.  The
summary screen shows all my
activity and all the items I
collected along the way.
Pokemon Go on Apple Watch will
help you to be the very best.
Thank you.
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; JOHN HANKE: Thanks, Tatsuo.
We are really excited to bring
you this new way to explore
Pokemon Go and get some
inspiration to get going, get
outside, and share with your
friends.  It will be shipping
before end of year.  Thank you.
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; JEFF WILLIAMS: Thanks, g
guys.  I can't wait to get
Pokemon Go for my Watch.  Maybe
I can finally break out of
level 2 and catch up with my
daughter.
Whether it's Pokemon Go or the
built-in apps, there are so
many rich features in watchOS
3, people are going to
absolutely love it.
(Applause)
We are going to keep pushing
Watch forward, and today I am
excited to introduce the next
generation of Apple Watch.
(Cheers and applause)
We call it Apple Watch Series
2, and it has been completely
reengineered.  It starts with a
feature that will change how
you use Apple Watch.  The first
Apple Watch was splash proof,
and Apple Watch Series 2 is
swim proof.
(Applause)
So you can wear it whether you
are swimming or surfing or just
doing that occasional ca
cannonball.  You can keep it
on.  It's rated water resistant
50 meters, which is the
industry standard for a swim
watch, but what that means is
the Watch needs to withstand
the water pressure equivalent
of being at a depth of 50
meters, and that's pretty deep.
And it's especially chal
challenging for a smartwatch
because there are so many
ingress points.  So our
engineers have been hard at
work developing new seals and
adhesives, and they have been
able to close all those entry
points except one -- the sp
speaker.  You see, a speaker
needs air to produce sound, and
if the air can get in, so can
the water, and that's a
problem.  So for Series 2, we
redesigned the speaker system,
and at the end of your workout,
we use the speaker itself to
eject the water.
(Applause)
We also wanted to make sure
Apple Watch was robust enough
not just for an occasional swim
but for people who want to swim
every day.  So we built a
simulator to test the effects
of swimming over multiple ye
years.  We put watches in
there, run them 24 hours a day
for weeks at a time, simulating
hundreds of thousands of
strokes, so you can wear your
watch with confidence in the
water.
We've also extended the work
of our fitness lab to swimming.
Now, calculating calorie burn
for swimming is really tricky,
and we've analyzed over 700
swimmers, different body types,
different abilities.  We've
hooked them up to st
state-of-the-art metabolic
equipment.  We've even drawn
blood samples to look at lactic
acid levels, and we used all
this body of information to
create an algorithm that will
give you the most accurate
calorie burn information while
you are swimming.  And we
created two new workouts, a
pool swim and an open water
swim, and during the workout,
you will get information like
lap count, pace, distance,
calorie burn.  What's more, the
Watch will learn more about you
over time.  It will get more
accurate over time.  It looks
at your stroke efficiency, not
that of some average swimmer,
and tailors just to you.  We
think swimmers are going to
absolutely love this.
(Applause)
Next, I'd like to talk about
the brains of Apple Watch
Series 2, and it starts with
our second generation System in
Package.  Last year we
introduced an industry first,
an entire system in a single
package, and S2 takes that to a
whole new level.  We've added a
dual-core processor that's up
to 50% faster.  We've added a
new, entirely new GPU that
delivers two times the graphics
performance.  And this powerful
chip opens up all kinds of
opportunities, both for
internal apps as well as
developers.  For example, Night
Sky, which is an app that
allows you to identify the
planets and constellations and
track the International Space
Station, they've been working
with S2, and they have been
able to add five times the
level of detail and more than
double the frame rate.  They
are running it at 60 frames a
second, which is just a crazy
amount of performance to be
wearing on your wrist.
(Applause)
Series 2 also features a new
second-generation display that
is more than two times brighter
than before.  It, in fact, is
the brightest display Apple has
ever shipped on any product at
1,000 nits.  That's a lot of
nits.  (Laughter).  And it
makes all the difference when
you are outside in the bright
sunlight.  It really does.
Really vivid.
Two of the most popular
activities in the world are
walking and running, and we
know there's times that people
want to do this without their
phone, so for those times,
we've added built-in GPS.
(Cheers and applause)
And this is really great.  You
can start right away.  For
those of you who have used a
GPS watch before, you know it
can sometimes take a long time
to connect to the satellites.
It seems like forever when you
are getting ready to work out.
With Apple Watch, you can
literally hit Start and begin
your workout.  During your w
workout, you will get G
GPS-accurate pace and distance.
And at the end of your w
workout, in the Activity app of
your phone, there will be a
route map color coded to show
your varying speeds.  And
developers can take advantage
of the built-in GPS.  I'd like
to give you an example of that.
I would like to invite to the
stage Hannah Catmur, Lead
Designer for ViewRanger.
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; HANNAH CATMUR: Hi.  I am
here today to show you
ViewRanger, the first-ever
hiking app on the new Apple
Watch, which gives you the
ability to join a hike like you
never have before.  So, I am
planning a trip to Yosemite.  I
have never been before, but I
hear it's beautiful.  With
ViewRanger, I selected these
three hikes ahead of time.
Apple Watch is made available
offline, which means I don't
need cell service to know where
I am.  I have the Half Dome
Cables on here, and at SHHH
miles, it's probably a bit
intense for this morning.
Let's take a look at the f
four-mile trail to Glacier
Point.  Let's get going.
Here I can see my directions.
And I can also scroll through
to see all of the exciting
views and destinations I have
coming up.  At any time, I can
swipe right to check in on the
map.  I can see my current
location and my route progress.
In fact, anytime, if I stray
too far from the path,
ViewRanger will let me know
about it.  This really wasn't
possible before, but now the
Apple Watch has integrated GPS,
ViewRanger can look out to make
sure I don't stray too far off
route.
From here we can check in on
the map.  We can get back on
track, and we can continue with
the hike.
So let's jump forward to about
halfway to the view of yo
Of Yosemite Falls.  With every
point of interest, ViewRanger
provides a quick fun fact.  So
let's tap into it.  Here we can
see that Yosemite Falls is
actually a hot spot for bird
watching, which is, in fact,
one of my favorite things to
do.  Hopefully we will see a
read-tailed hawk on the way
towards the summit.
Here we are in the final
sprint as we head towards
Glacier Point.  ViewRanger k
knows when I've reached the end
of the hike.  I then have the
option to either finish or to
keep going if I'd like.  We'll
tap Finish.  My Activity rings
will fill up, and I am all set
to enjoy the rest of Yosemite.
That's ViewRanger, the fi
first-ever hiking app to take
advantage of the new GPS on
Apple Watch.  We are really
excited for you guys to try it
on your next hike.  Thank you.
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; JEFF WILLIAMS: Thanks,
Hannah.
So many opportunities with the
features of Series 2.  Series 2
comes in a wide variety of
styles.  We have cases in
aluminum and stainless steel,
as well as a new material we've
been working on for quite some
time, ceramic.
(Applause)
This new white Apple Watch in
ceramic has this gorgeous pe
pearl-like shine.  The finish
is remarkably smooth.  It's
actually four times harder than
stainless steel, so it's this
ultimate combination of beauty
and strength.  And it looks
great paired with a variety of
bands.  We think it's going to
be a wonderful addition to the
Apple Watch family.
We also are offering Series 2
in Hermes models.  Last year we
partnered with Hermes, a
company known for craftsmanship
and elegance and style, and for
Series 2, there are beautiful
new colors of the iconic double
tour and single tour, as well
as two new bands, this si
single-tour deployment buckle,
and a new double-buckle cuff.
We think people are really
going to enjoy these.
(Applause)
So that's Apple Watch Series
2.  It is faster.  It is
brighter.  It is water
resistant so you can swim with
it.  It's got built-in GPS.
And it's got all of the power
of watchOS 3.  It is also built
according to our strict
environmental standards,
something we care deeply about.
This is made in a responsible
way.
We think Apple Watch is the
ultimate device for a healthy
life, and we expect it to be
popular with everybody, but we
think it will be especially
popular with runners.  And we
wanted to do something special
for them.  We couldn't think of
a better way to do that than to
partner with a company that
knows runners better than
anyone else in the world.  They
are the number one sports and
fitness brand in the world, and
that is Nike.
(Cheers and applause)
We've worked with Nike for over
a decade, and we couldn't be
more excited today to announce
Apple Watch Nike+.
(Applause)
It's a watch designed spe
specifically with runners in
mind.  It features this
beautiful perforated band
that's stretchy, it's light,
it's breathable.  It's paired
with our lightweight aluminum
case, which is ideal for
running.  And we are so excited
about it, and to tell you more
about this, I'd like to bring
to the stage Trevor Edwards,
President of the Nike brand.
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; TREVOR EDWARDS: Good
morning.  Whoo!  It's been such
a great partnership working
with Apple.  Apple and Nike
share a passion to make life
easier and more fun, and we
look forward to continuing this
amazing journey together.
Nike has always been about
inspiration and innovation for
every athlete, and it all began
40 years ago with a deep
relationship with runners, and
that obsession continues to
this day.
Today, sports and fitness are
a bigger part of people's
lives, and more and more people
want to get out and run.  But
getting started on your own and
staying motivated can be tough.
So, more and more people are
looking for help and turning to
running devices to actually
help them.  But these devices
are complex, they are clut
cluttered, and they are
difficult to use.  And, of
course, they don't support what
a runner wants to do when he
just wants to get out and go
for a quick run.  It's a
problem, and Nike and Apple
have solved it.
The Apple Watch Nike+.  This
isn't just a watch; it's your
perfect running partner.  It's
simple, it's fun, and it's easy
to use.  And we think it
delivers the best -- the best
-- running experience that's
out there.  Starting a run has
never been easier, and we give
you a shortcut that takes you
straight into your run.  And if
you prefer, you can just tell
Siri to start a run, and off
you go.  It's that simple.
When you if out for a run, you
don't want to be distracted.
So we give you just what you
need at a glance, your distance
or your pace, on a big, clear
screen.  And if you are the
type, though, who really wants
a lot of detail, we've always
got advanced mode just for you.
But one of the biggest hurdles
that all runners face is
actually motivation.  So we
started with a simple idea of
an invitation.  Are We Running
Today?  And we motivate you
through insightful invitations
personalized just for you.
Been a few days since your last
run?  Maybe the weather isn't
perfect or it is perfect today,
you can get out.  And if your
friends have a head start, we
will let you know.  Jeff's got
two miles ahead.  Clearly I've
got to catch up.
(Applause)
We also know -- thank you.  We
also know that those who run on
Sundays are more active and
will be more active throughout
the rest of the week, so every
Sunday we invite you to join
runners from all around the
world to run at your own pace
wherever you are.  We call it
Just Do It Sundays.  With
invitations like these, running
is made easier and simply a
part of your life.
But it doesn't end there.
With this watch, you are also a
part of Nike+ Run Club, which
gives you personalized coa
coaching, recommends the best
gear for you, and gives you
access to live runs in cities
and communities all around the
globe.
With the Apple Watch Nike+,
the world's best running club
comes to life with everyone and
everything you need to be
better.
Now, most devices today, they
focus solely on data and
metrics.  Not this one.  The
Apple Watch Nike+ focuses on
you and your life.  It's a
powerful device with a simple
solution, your perfect running
partner.  And it's available in
four amazing cool colors, and
we can't wait for you to try it
out.
(Applause)
Thank you.
(Cheers and applause)
It's a journey that we are on
together, and this is really
just the start of exciting
things to come.  Thanks very
much.
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; JEFF WILLIAMS: Thanks,
Trevor.  I feel faster already.
(Laughter)
We are really excited to bring
Apple Watch Nike+ to the wo
world's largest community of
runners.  Apple Watch Series 2
will be priced at $369.  Apple
Watch Nike+ will also be priced
at $369.  And we are keeping in
the line our original Apple
Watch, but we've done something
with it.  We've added the same
dual-score processor that's in
Series 2, so it's just as
snappy, and we are calling it
Series 1, and it starts at just
$269.
You can preorder both Series 1
and Series 2 on September 9.
WatchOS 3 is available on the
13th.  And the Watches will go
on sale, both Series 1 and
Series 2 the following week.
Apple Watch Nike+ will be
available late October.
That's Apple Watch.  Back to
you, Tim.
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Thank you, Jeff.
We are so proud of the Apple
Watch and the unbelievable
positive response from the
users, and we can't wait for
people to get their hands on
the new one.
Next up is iPhone.
(Cheers and applause)
iPhone is the industry gold
standard.  The phone by which
all other smartphones are
compared.  The iPhone has
transformed the way we do
things every day, and in the
process, it's become truly a
cultural phenomenon, touching
so many lives from people all
around the world.  And there's
a reason why you see so many
iPhones everywhere you look.
We've now sold over a billion
of them.
(Applause)
This makes iPhone the
bestselling product of its kind
in the history of the world.
Now, iPhone, like all of our
products at Apple, provide u
users the best experience
available by tightly
integrating hardware, software,
and services.  And, of course,
the software that powers iPhone
is iOS, the world's most
advanced mobile operating
system.  We are about to launch
iOS 10, which is our biggest
iOS release ever.  It is jam
packed with new features to
enrich your daily experiences.
For instance, you can simply
just lift your iPhone to wake
it.  We've added Siri
capability for apps from the
App Store.  So I can say:  Get
me a Lyft to SFO.  You can book
a ride just by voice.  We've
added even more intelligence
through machine learning into
our QuickType keyboard with
contextual prediction.
Maps has been beautifully
redesigned, and you can use
apps here as well to book a
reservation or book a ride, all
without leaving the Maps app.
I'd like to take a moment and
talk about HomeKit.  This is a
huge moment for home auto
automation.  This is the first
time that home automation has
been integrated into a major
platform.  And it all starts
here with the Home app, which
makes it unbelievably easy to
set up and manage devices
throughout the home, whether
you are at home or away.  With
iOS 10, you can manage your
home right from Control Center,
and with Siri as well.
And HomeKit now supports
accessories across all of the
major categories of home
automation, from garage doors
to security to everything in
between.  And virtually every
major manufacturer of home
automation devices now supports
HomeKit.  In fact, there's over
a hundred products coming to
market this year, and so many
more in the pipeline.
All you have to do is look for
this label, "Works with Apple
HomeKit."  They are super easy
to set up and use with the new
Home app in iOS 10.  We are
really excited about HomeKit,
and we think this is going to
be a really big deal.
(Applause)
Now, we are also excited about
Messages and the new features
in Messages.  You can change
the behavior and meaning of
your message with these new
bubble effects.  And now
there's some new full-screen
effects like confetti and
fireworks.  And new stickers.
Just peel them, place them
anywhere you want.  They are
available in the new App Store
for iMessage, along with some
other great apps, and you can
easily use these apps to
create, to share content, to
make payments, and more, all
without leaving Messages.
So, that's a quick update on
iOS 10, the world's most
advanced mobile operating
system, with some incredible
new features.  Now, of course,
the world's most advanced
mobile operating system
deserves the most advanced
smartphone.  And here it is.
(Cheers and applause)
It's the best iPhone that we
have ever created.  This is
iPhone 7.
(Cheers and applause)
It has a gorgeous new design,
and I'd like to have Jony tell
you more about it.
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; JONY IVE: We have created a
product that is the most
deliberate evolution of our
original founding design.  An
aluminum body and formed sheet
of glass describe a singular
shape.  One made with very few,
very precisely engineered pa
parts.  Our obsession remains
to continuously simplify and
improve.  From sculpting the
camera housing directly out of
the aluminum body to embedding
the antenna within the
enclosure, essentially making
it disappear, each refinement
serves to bring absolute unity
and efficiency to the design.
To define one truly
uninterrupted form, we've
developed a whole new process
to achieve a high gloss black
finish.  This begins with
rotational 3D polishing, a
specialized compound flows over
the intricate geometries of the
housing, removing imperf
imperfections, establishing a
seamlessness between materials,
and producing a pristine mi
mirror-like surface.
The enclosure then goes
through an anodizeation pro
process, which creates a
protective oxide layer.  A
single-component dye is ab
absorbed through a capillary
effect to ensure maximum
saturation while actually
becoming part of the surface
itself.
Finally, a magnetized ul
ultra-fine ion particle bath is
used to polish the anodized
layer to a superior high shine.
When complete, iPhone 7 is the
most singular, the most evolved
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: We are so excited
about iPhone 7.  It makes all
the things you do every day so
much better.  To tell you more
about it, I'd like to invite my
colleague Phil Schiller up to
the stage.  Phil?
&gt;&gt; PHIL SCHILLER: Well, good
morning, everyone.  I am
excited.  I hope you are.  This
is -- yeah, somebody is.  This
is the best iPhone we have ever
made.  We are going to cover it
with ten major features.  We
are going to get right started
with number one.  You have
already heard about it -- the
design.  Tim and Jony have told
you that there is a beautiful
new refined design for iPhone
7.  It starts with this new
finish we call jet black.  It
is absolutely stunning.
(Applause)
It is a high-gloss finish, so
it's a seamless surface between
the glass and the aluminum back
all around.  It is a stainless
steel Apple logo.  The new
integrated antennas are built
so subtly you can barely see
them at all anymore.  And of
course, the enclosure creates
the housing for the camera.  It
is a beautiful new design.
There is a second new black,
we call it simply "black."
(Laughter)
It is bead-blasted aluminum.
It diffuses light.  It is a
black logo.  And it looks very
cool, very high tech.
The new iPhone 7 also looks
beautiful in gold, and in
silver, and of course, rose
gold.
(Applause)
Number two, something we use
hundreds of times a day, the
Home button.  The Home button
is quintessential Apple desn.
It is so simple yet so
powerful.  We use it throughout
our day.  We click it to go
home.  We double-click it to
bring in multiitasking.  We
hold it down to invoke Siri.
We can program it through
accessibility.  You can put
your finger on it and read your
fingerprint with Touch ID.  You
can double-tap it to bring the
screen down in reachability,
and of course, hold it near a
terminal to pay with Apple Pay.
It does so many things for us,
and we've completely redesigned
it to make it more responsive,
more reliable, and even
customizable in iPhone 7.
Now, we've done this before.
We've changed our input devices
in big ways.  You may remember
with the iPod, it started with
a mechanical click wheel, then
we updated to an
electrotrostatic wheel, and it
was so much better.  We've done
it recently in MacBook Pro.
We've brought out the Force
Touch Trackpad, and it's the
best Trackpad we've ever had in
a notebook.  And we are doing
this with the Home button.
We've reengineered it.  It's
now force sensitive, solid
state.  It works together in
combination with a n
new-generation Taptic Engine.
This Taptic Engine is more
responsive, puts out a wider
range of frequencies, and it
creates in real time an
incredible feel with the new
Home button.  In fact, it's so
useful we use it throughout the
user experience.  So if you do
a quick action, like moving a
widget, it gives you a nice
taptic feedback.  There's
unique feedbacks for
notifications and messages and
even your ringtones, and it's
amazing because it can be
programmed by third-party
applications, and the
applications that have started
to work on iPhone 7, taking
advantage of this Taptic En
Engine, are creating new
feelings and experiences that
could not have been created
before in a smartphone.  It's
really incredible.
Number three, the new
enclosure in iPhone 7 and
iPhone 7 Plus are water and
dust resistant.
(Applause)
Now, it's incredibly important
to the team to ensure that we
protect the great feeling and
experience that we all love
about our iPhones with the
buttons and switches.  To do
that and provide this
resistance meant reengineering
it from the inside out in many
ways, including new seals and
new adhesives.  In our tests,
it is IP67 protection standard.
What does this mean for all of
us?  Well, even the least
coordinated among us don't have
to worry in case some unusual
mishap happens that your iPhone
will be safe from water or d
dust.
(Applause)
Number four, let's talk about
the camera.  The camera is
perhaps the most beloved
feature by many of us in our
iPhones, and customers take
absolutely stunning photo
photographs.  You can see them
around the world in the Shot on
iPhone campaign.  They are
amazing, and they send us them
every single day, more pictures
to be included in our campaign,
because it is an incredible
camera.  And just wait until
they get their hands on the new
camera system in the iPhone 7.
It is a huge advancement in
photography for cell phones.
Everything about it is
entirely new.  There's an
optical image stabilizer in all
iPhones, 7 and 7 Plus, helps
steady from shaking hands.
(Applause)
There's a wider F 1.le
aperture lens that lets 50%
more light on the sensor.
There is a new six-element lens
so you can get sharper images
edge to edge with that 1.8
aperture.  And there is an a
all-new sensor, large pixels,
60% faster and 30% more energy
efficient.
Even the flash is all new.
Our True Tone flash, in the
same aperture, now has four
LEDs.  It puts out 50% more
light, reaches 50% further, and
the engineering team has come
up with this really cool
feature, a flicker sensor.
What does that do?  The flicker
sensor reads the flickering of
artificial lighting and can
compensate for it in the photos
and videos you take.  This is
really, really big in terms of
image quality.
But behind it all is the
brains of the camera, the image
signal processor.  And this
enables so much of the unique
quality that we get in our
pictures we take with iPhone,
and the ISP and the new chip in
the iPhone 7 is twice the
throughput of our previous
versions.  What does this ISP
do?  Well, I am going to take a
quick walk-through of some of
the things the ISP does every
time we take a picture.
The first thing it does is
read the machine and uses
machine learning to look for
objects and people and bodies
within it.
Then it automatically sets
exposure, sets focus using our
Focus Pixels, sets the color
with white balance.  In fact,
for the first time, captures
wide color, cinema-standard
wide color.  It balances off
with tone mapping.  It does
noise reduction.  And even if
it needs to, it can take
multiple photos and fuse them
together into one to give you
the perfect image.  This
happens every time we take a
picture.  In fact, the ISP is
so smart it is performing 100
billion operations every time
we take a picture.  And it does
it in just 25 milliseconds.
This truly is a supercomputer
for photos.
(Applause)
What matters most is the
pictures you can take with the
iPhone 7.  So of course, we've
given iPhone 7s to a number of
great photographers and asked
them to show us what's possible
directly with this incredible
camera, and they were so blown
away.  I want to use one quote
of what photographers had to
say about this.  Christopher
Anderson said:  This iPhone is
going to be a part of any
professional's repertoire of
tools.  The camera didn't just
handle low light, it rendered
the separation of colors in a
way that reminds me of film.
Just beautiful.  That is
remarkable praise from a great
photographer.  So I am going to
show you a few pictures that he
and other photographers took
directly from iPhone 7, and
these have not been retouched
in any way.  So here's one.
This is an absolutely beautiful
photograph.
(Applause)
This is a high-speed camera.
He is not floating there.  It
shows just how great it is and
how sharp the focus.  It takes
vebl pictures, whether you are
using black and white or color.
And the colors, because we
capture wide color gamut images
now, are much richer,
particularly in the greens and
some of the reds.
Unfortunately, from the slide
machine up to this projection
system, you don't get the full
breadth of the gamut of wide
colors, so what you are seeing
here, as beautiful as it is,
isn't as beautiful as it
actually is in the photo and
you can see it on your iPhone.
And here's an example of l
low-light photography.  So much
improved.  It's really great.
So customers are going to love
taking pictures with iPhone 7.
They are also going to love
taking Live Photos.  They are
already fun, and they've gotten
even better with iPhone 7.  Now
we apply video image
stabilization when you take a
Live Photo.  You can edit them
after you have shot them, like
crop them or apply filters, and
developers can capture and edit
Live Photos within their
applications with iOS 10.
Developers are really excited
that in iOS 10 you can now
capture RAW DNG files directly
from the camera sensor and do
even more complex editing.  And
for the first time with iPhone
7, they can also get wide color
in their photos that they take
as well.  So, this is the best
camera we have ever made on any
iPhone.
We also have the best camera
we have ever had on the front
size as well.  There's a new
7-megapixel FaceTime HD camera
for those selfies and calls we
make.  This is up from 5
megapixelss.  The sensor
includes new pixel technologies
we used on the back side, like
deep trench isolation.  If you
remember what that is, it helps
us get sharper images as the
pixels get closer together.  It
also captures wide color images
and does auto image
stabilization.  This shot you
see up here on the screen, that
was taken from the front-side
camera, unedited exactly, as it
can take a beautiful selfie.
So this is the iPhone 7 ca
camera, new 12-megapixel camera
system with optical image
stabilization, wider f/1.8
aperture; six elements in the
lens that senses 60% faster.
Now a quad-LED True Tone flash.
Our incredibly fast ISP and
wide color capture.  It is the
best camera ever in an iPhone.
(Applause)
So, if you can't tell, I love
cameras.  I love them.  And
this has got me so excited
because if that is the best
camera we have ever made in
iPhone, what is left for iPhone
7?  And this is what we are
doing on iPhone 7 Plus.  It's
plus a second camera.  There's
now two 12-megapixel cameras
built in to the iPhone 7 Plus.
One has the wide-angle
28-millimeter lens, the same as
the iPhone 7.  The other is a
telephoto 66-millimeter lens.
Why have two complete cameras
with two lenses?  Well, to
explain it, let me show you a
traditional point-and-shoot or
DSLR and how the lens can work.
As you know, we have many of
these cameras in our lives, you
can change the focal length of
your lens to zoom in.  That's
how we get a zoom feature.  And
that works great when you have
a large camera with a big lens
on it.  You can move in and o
out.  That isn't so great on
the lens you want to put in
something that goes in your
pocket or your purse.  So we
know with two cameras and two
different lenses, we can create
a zoom feature built in to the
iPhone.  It takes an incredible
amount of hardware and software
to do it in a way that we can
all enjoy, and the team has
done something remarkable.  So
how does it work?  The same as
before.  You go into the camera
app to take a picture.  But now
there's a new button right
there on the screen -- let me
blow it up a teeny bit.  It
says 1x, right above the
shutter.  When you go to take a
picture, it is using the
wide-angle lens and taking a
picture as aels.  But now with
this button you can do one of
two things.  First you can just
tap it and it jumps to 2x.  Now
you are taking a picture with a
telephoto lens.  You are
getting the same high-quality
12-megapixel picture with a
beautiful optical lens, no
software needed.
The second thing you can do is
you can put your finger on it
and drawing across it, and you
can zoom from 1x to 5x.  As you
go beyond 2x, you are doing
software zoom.  But now, since
it's starting with that
telephoto lens, the quality of
that image is four times better
than before with software zoom.
In fact, it's so much better
we decided to push it even
further all the way up to 10x.
So now -- (Applause)
So, as you see here, now with
iPhone 7 Plus, you can go from
1x to 10x, optical zoom at 2x,
and great software zoom after
that.
Here is an example of two
photos side by side.  The one
on the left taken at 1x, the
one on the right at 2x, both
with beautiful optical lens
quality, both are great
examples of taking low-light
pictures now with incredible
new cameras in iPhone 7 Plus.
So that's the camera on iPhone
7 Plus, joining iPhone 7, with
its great new zoom feature.
There's one other use of this
camera that we challenged our
engineering team to do as an
extra credit project.  It
really was.  It's something
that is incredibly challenging
and takes a lot of amazing
invention, but what they have
been doing is astounding.  And
it's something that's a big
breakthrough in photography,
and we want to give you a sneak
peek of this feature.
To explain it, I am going to
bring up a picture.  This is a
picture taken with a very h
high-end camera.  It will help
us illustrate the feature we
are trying to achieve.  Let me
bring up a picture.  You have
seen this beautiful portrait.
The gentleman in the front is
pin sharp in focus.  That
background has a beautiful
blur.  This is called shallow
depth of field.  This is a
technique that's really useful
for things like portrait ure.
It's something that is
illustrative of a great camera
that has often a very big
sensor, like a full-frame
sensor, or a really big, fast
lens.  And the quality of that
background blur, that's what's
called Bokeh.  The higher the
quality of the bokeh, usually
the more advanced and higher
quality the camera and lens
system.  The result is it feels
almost 3D, like the person is
popping off the screen.  It's a
really beautiful photo.  So our
goal is to try to do something
like this using the two cameras
in the iPhone 7 Plus.  What the
engineering team has been
doing, hardware and software
working together, is truly
remarkable.  What they are able
to do is when we take a picture
is to use the ISP to scan the
scene.  Use machine learning to
recognize people and faces.
And then create a depth map of
that image from the two cameras
and the software.  Keep the
people in the front sharp in
focus and apply a beautiful
blur to the background.  This
is a huge breakthrough in what
can be done on a smartphone in
photography.
So how do you do it?  Well, it
couldn't be easier.  Again, we
go to the camera app, you go to
take a picture.  Where you
normally select the style of
the picture, so panorama or
square, there's a new style
that says "portrait."  You
select portrait, it
automatically jumps to using
the telephoto lens because that
56-millimeter lens is great for
portrait lens, and
automatically you see the depth
effect.  Now, what's remarkable
is that before you take a
picture, as you are looking at
your iPhone screen, you are
seeing that blur in the
background.  It is being
generated in real time as you
are looking at your screen.
Even high-end DSLRs can't do
real-time deep depth preview in
their screens.  This is an
incredible breakthrough.
Now I am going to show you the
first picture we've ever shown
the world of a depth of field
photo taken from an iPhone 7
Plus with this new feature.
Before I do, I have to come
clean on something because I
wasn't entirely honest before.
The picture I showed you
before, this was I can at t
thaten on an iPhone 7 Plus.
(Applause)
It is stunning.  We've given
some photographers early access
to the 7 Plus and software
feature, and they have been
blown away by how it performs.
Let me give you one quote from
a photographer.  Jason Nocito
said I love the depth of field
capabilities and the ability to
shoot fast without losing
sharpness.  This iPhone proves
you don't need a five-figure
rig to be a great photographer.
This camera is gonna change
the game.
Now, we are not saying to
throw out your DSLRs and that
iPhone replaces all the DSLRs.
What we are saying is this is
the best camera we have ever
made in an iPhone.  This is the
best camera ever made in any
smartphone.  For many of the
customers who have it, it will
probably be the best camera
they have ever owned to date.
But more importantly, it allows
them to create beautiful
pictures with incredible
creative tools.
So let me show you two more
examples taken from the iPhone
7 Plus with its depth of field.
Here is another photo.  That's
absolutely beautiful.  One m
more.  It is an incredible t
tool.  It's not for every style
of picture you are going to
take, but for the ones you want
to use it on, it's a pretty big
breakthrough.
So, how will iPhone 7 Plus u
users get this great feature?
Simple.  It will be a free
software update later this year
to all iPhone 7 Plus users.  So
that's the camera.
(Applause)
Next, let's talk about the
Retina HD display.  The Retina
HD display is the best display
on any smartphone.  And in
iPhone 7 and 7 Plus, they get
even better.  They are now 25%
brighter than the 6s and
6s Plus.  For the first time
they display wide color gamut,
that cinema P3 standard colors.
And we do end-to-end color
management from the
manufacturer in the factory to
the photos you take with the
camera to what you see on the
display are all color managed
in a beautiful way.  And don't
forget we integrate within the
Retina HD display our 3D Touch
layer.  This is an important
element of the user interface,
and in iOS 10, the team has
taken great use of this, so we
are going to use it more
throughout our day in very
powerful ways.
So we wanted to show you one
example of an app taking
advantage of all of this,
taking advantage of the Retina
HD display and its wide color,
of the camera's built in iPhone
7, and of course, 3D Touch.  We
wanted to show you a photo app,
and who knows photos and apps
better than Instagram?  I am
very excited to bring up Ian
Spalter, Head of Design at
Instagram.  Ian?
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; IAN SPALTER: Good morning,
everybody.  I am excited to
share with you what we've built
to take advantage of this new
iPhone's gorgeous wide color
screen and dual lens camera.
About a month ago, we launched
a in you product called
Instagram Stories, and we have
seen people sharing moments
ranging from their everyday
lives to behind the scenes at
the Olympics.  So let's jump
into the stories camera using
the new 3D Touch quick action.
The first thing we love about
this new iPhone is this
beautiful zoom that goes o
optically into 2x without
losing any resolution.  We
built a new zoom UI with haptic
feedback so you can really feel
when you push into that digital
zoom.  But now let's take a
photo.
(Laughter)
(Applause)
Thank you.  Check out how
bright and vivid the colors are
thanks to the new wide color
capture of the new camera.  So,
photos don't always capture the
moment fully, so with a tap of
a button, we used a live photos
API to quickly create a
boomerang to bring the moment
to life.  You can also import
your existing live photos and
do the same thing.
This is awesome, but we wanted
to go a step further and really
take full advantage of this
wide color gamut screen.  So we
built a new filter to do just
that by pushing into parts of
the color spectrum that just
weren't possible with sRGB.  So
with this new filter, you can
see colors pop in a way that
you've never seen before.  In
fact, we've updated all of our
photo filters to take advantage
of wide gamut, so no matter
what your favorite filter is,
you are going to be
experiencing all of your
Instagram photos in full,
vibrant color.
(Applause)
And finally, once you are
happy with what you've created,
you can share the moment with
friends with a single tap, and
then if one of them replies,
our iOS 10 rich notifications
show you the image right there
in the push notification.
So this new version of
Instagram will be launching
later this year, and we are
really excited to see what you
all create with Instagram and
the new iPhone.  Thank you.
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; PHIL SCHILLER: Six, let's
talk about audio.  First, we
use the built-in speaker in our
iPhone all the time.  We use it
to listen to music, especially
with friends.  We listen to it
to make FaceTime calls, watch
TV shows, watch movies, do
speakerphone calls.  It is
critical to our experience with
our phones.  And the speakers
we have built in to iPhone 7
and 7 Plus are a huge jump
forward in audio quality.  The
first time, there's stereo
speakers.
(Applause)
One is at the bottom, the
other is at the top.  They
sound great in portrait and
amazing in landscape.  They
also put out twice the volume
of the speakers in the iPhone
6s and 6s Plus, and they sound
better because they have an
increased dynamic range.  So
you have to take a listen to
these incredible speakers.
They really will blow you away.
Number seven, EarPods.  Apple
EarPods are the most popular
headphones in the world.  And
with iPhone 7 and 7 Plus, we
are moving to connecting them
over Lightning.  Well, why over
Lightning?  Well, first you may
not remember -- I certainly do
-- but from the start, we
designed Lightning to be a
great digital audio connector.
Among all the other things it
does, it provides a digital
audio stream, it provides power
to your headphones or speakers,
it provides content music
control right within its
digital connection.  And this
may surprise you, but there are
now in the world over 900
million Lightning-enabled
devices.  It is perhaps the
largest digital audio
connection in the world.  And
there are speakers and
headphones designed to take
advantage of it, and they do
great things.  Here's one
example.  This is from JBL.
This is the Reflect Aware
workout headphone.  It's li
lightweight, affordable,
provides active noise
cancellation.  In fact, with an
app on your iPhone, it's
adaptive and you can adjust how
much exterior noise you want to
let in or not.  And it does it
all without batteries or
charging because it works
directly over that Lightning
connector.  Simply not possible
on just an analog port.
So we are taking the
headphones in iPhone 7 and 7
Plus to lightning, and we are
including them in the box with
each device.
Now, we know there are people
in the world who do have some
analog old connected devices
out there.  So we have also
made this.  It's an adapter,
Lightning to min phono adapter.
We are going to include that
in the box with every iPhone 7
and 7 Plus as well.
(Applause)
Now, some people have asked
why we would remove the analog
headphone jack from the iPhone.
I mean, it's been with us a
really long time.
(Laughter)
I am sure you know that the
source of this miniphono jack
is over a hundred years old,
used to help quickly exchange
in switchboards.  Well, the
reason to move on -- I am going
to give you three of them, but
it really comes down to one
word -- courage.  The courage
to move on, do something new
that betters all of us, and our
team has tremendous courage.
So first, we've shown that we
can use Lightning for our
in-box headphones and to adapt
to all the older devices
through analog interfaces, and
it is a great connector for
doing that and is a very large
base of users who can all take
advantage of it.
But second -- and this is
really important -- our
smartphones are packed with
technologies, and we all want
more.  We want bigger, brighter
displays; we want larger
batteries; we want faster
processors; we want stereo
speakers; we want Taptic
Engines.  We want all of that,
and it's all fighting for space
within that same enclosure, and
maintaining an ancient si
single-purpose analog big
connector doesn't make sense
because that space is at a
premium.
And third -- and I think this
is most important of all --
when you have a vision of how
audio -- the audio experience
can be, you want to get there
as fast as you can and make it
as great as it can be.  And we
do have a vision for how audio
should work on mobile devices.
And that takes us to our next
feature.  Wireless.  Up till
now, no one has taken on the
challenge to really deliver the
audio experience wirelessly
between your mobile device and
your headphones in a way that
takes advantage of the
opportunities to do something
new and do something great.
And up till now, no one has
taken on the challenge of
fixing the things that are
difficult to do in those
wireless experiences and made
it easy so that we all want to
enjoy them.  And it makes no
sense to tether ourselves with
cables to our mobile devices,
but until someone takes on
these challenges, that's what
we do.  Our team at Apple has
worked so hard to create
something new that delivers on
the opportunity of how good a
wireless experience can be, and
they've worked hard to deal
with the challenges that have
been left there and no one has
taken on.  So that is why today
we are so excited to show you a
new product from Apple called
Apple AirPods.
(Cheers and applause)
And here they are.
&gt;&gt; We believe in a wireless
future, a future where all of
your devices intuitively
connect.  This belief drove the
design of our new wireless
They have been made possible
with the development of the new
Apple design W1 chip.  It is
the first of its kind to
produce intelligent,
high-efficiency playback while
delivering a consistent and
reliable connection.  Infrared
sensors detect when each AirPod
is in your ear, so they only
play once you are ready to l
listen.  Motion Accelerometers
also respond to your touch,
allowing you to access Siri
with a double-tap.  When you
are speaking, voice
accelerometers recognize the
vibration and source of your
voice.  Then, working with a
pair of beamforming micro
microphones, reduce external
noise.  Each AirPod provides up
to five hours of listening on a
single charge.  While the
compact wireless charging case
delivers more than 24 hours of
battery life.
The W1 chip enables
intelligent connection to all
your Apple devices and allows
you to instantly switch between
whichever one you are using.
And of course, the new
wireless AirPods deliver
incredible sound.  We are just
at the beginning of a truly
wireless future we've been
working towards for many years.
, where technology enables the
seamless and automatic
connection between you and your
devices.
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; PHIL SCHILLER:
Congratulations to the team who
has worked so hard on this.  It
is a breakthrough design.  The
AirPods deliver truly an Apple
magical experience.  When you
try it, you are just going to
be blown away.
How do you set them up?  You
simply put a pair of EarPods
near your iPhone and open your
case.  The user interface pops
up and says Connect, and you
tap Connect.  That's it.
There's no step two, nothing
else to do.  You simply con
connect.  And that one step
also connects you with your
Apple Watch, so you are
automatically set up for both
your iPhone and your Apple
Watch.  You can start l
listening.  And as you have
playback on either device, the
EarPods automatically switch to
whatever device you are using.
In fact, we also use iCloud to
propagate that setup across
your iPads and your Macs as
well, so one-step setup across
all your devices.  It's that
easy.
They are an incredible audio
experience.  You can listen to
beautiful music in stereo, or
if you want to use one, just to
talk to Siri or make a phone
call, it automatically routes
the audio across whatever you
choose to do.  There's no
buttons.  There's no switching.
There's no pairing.  There's
no unpairing.  Those things are
of the past.
And it all started with a
brand-new chip, W1 chip, Ap
Apple's first wireless chip.
And there's so much technology
packed into each AirPod.
There's the chip.  There's dual
accelerometers, optical sen
sensors, beamforming
microphones, antennas,
batteries.  It is a tech
technical tour de force in this
unique AirPod.
There is a battery built into
the case so you can recharge
directly from the battery in
the case for up to 4 hours of
listening and then plug in
lightning once you want to
charge the case and the AirPods
together at once.  And they are
so small you will want to carry
them along with you everywhere.
Here they are alongside our
wired EarPods.
So that is the breakthrough
AirPods based on our W1 chip
and, at the same time, Beats is
also coming out with a new line
of headphones all also taking
advantage of this W1 chip and
doing the same great work with
our software to make the
experience easy to use.  So
today Beats is launching the
new Beats Solo3 Wireless,
incredible audio quality to 40
hours of listening time using
that W1 chip.  And for wor
workouts, Powerbeats3 Wireless,
the best active headphones, and
now they use our W1 chip as
well for incredible sound and
battery life.  And an entirely
new line, Beatsx.  This is
affordable, light, comfortable
headphone for all throughout
your day.  Those three plus the
new AirPods means now a br
brand-new wireless experience
for everyone regardless of what
kind of style of headphone you
want to wear.
And that's wireless.
(Cheers and applause)
Let's talk about Apple Pay.
Our customers love using Apple
Pay.  And this is amazing.  In
the U.S., merchants tell us
that over 90% of wireless
transactions on contactless
payment are now made with Apple
Pay.  It is a huge hit.  And
with the advances in iOS 10, it
gets even easier to keep all
your credit cards, your loyalty
cards safely in your Apple
Wallet on your iPhone.  We are
trying to bring it around the
world as quickly as we can, and
the team is launching new
country this is fall.  I want
to talk about one of them,
Japan.  Yeah, we got a hoo
right out here.  Japan.  You
may know that in Japan, they
use a different version of NFC
called FeliCa.  So for the
iPhone 7 and 7 Plus that we are
bringing to Japan, we are
including FeliCa technology, as
well as Apple Watch Series 2
will also include FeliCa
technology.  And with that in
place, then we can roll out
Apple Pay in Japan, and we are
going to do that in October.
At the same time, the Apple
Maps team is going to roll out
Transit in Japan, because
that's the perfect fit, Transit
in Maps, the ability to figure
out what it's going to cost to
get on your route and to be
able to pay it automatically
with your Apple Watch or your
iPhone.
So that's Apple Pay, and that
particulars us to number ten.
(Applause)
Honestly, I am almost
embarrassed that we have this
one till last because this
easily could have been the
first.  It is performance.  And
if you are paying attention,
you know Apple's chip team is
killing it in performance.
What they are doing year after
year is remarkable.  Every year
the iPhone is the fastest
smartphone in the market, and
that's continued even to this
day.  But what's happening
today with iPhone 7 and 7 Plus
blows that all away because we
have a new generation chip in
the iPhone 7, and it's called
A10 Fusion.
(Applause)
A10 Fusion is a 64-bit
four-core processor with over
3.3 billion transistors.  It is
a rocket ship.
First, it has two cores that
are high-performance cores.
These high-performance cores
run a full 40% faster than the
A9 chip in the iPhone 6 and
6s Plus.  If you are coming
from an iPhone 6 or 6 Plus,
it's twice as fast than the A8.
Here is what the team has been
doing over the years.  The A10
Fusion now 120 times faster
than the original iPhone.  And
look at the last three years,
from the 5s to the 6, from the
6 to the 6s, and now the 7, the
jumps in performance are just
staggering.
I said there are four cores.
The other two are what we call
high-efficiency cores.  They
run at one-fifth the power of
the high-performance core.  So
when you are doing something
that isn't performance limited
by the CPU, like checking your
email, that can run on the
high-efficiency core and get
longer battery life.  So how do
we decide what runs on which
core?  There's a new Apple
design Performance Controller
that in real-time makes sure
processes are running for
maximum performance or maximum
battery life.
In addition, we've got amazing
graphics in the A10.  It's a
new GPU.  It's a six-core
graphics chip that is 50% f
faster than the A9 and three
times faster than the A8.  This
is remarkable.  And it does it,
again, with efficiency in mind.
Two-therds of the power of the
A9.  Half the power of the A8
in graphics.
I've got to bring this chart
up as well.  240 times faster
than the original iPhone.  The
graphics performance year over
year here is staggering.  If
you combine the CPU
performance, the graphics
performance all running
efficiently, and there is
absolutely no question A10
Fusion is the most powerful
chip ever in a smartphone.
(Applause)
More importantly for all of
us, A10 Fusion is going to
enable apps and titles that
were simply not possible in
mobile devices before.  For
example, games.  This is from
Codemasters.  It's a new racing
game.  F1 2016.  This is
console-level gaming on an
iPhone because of A10.  Takes
advantage of the GPU.  It also
delivers graphics that use the
wide color gamut of the dis
display.  It takes advantage of
the stereo speakers and
utilizes the Taptic Engine for
new level of feel when you are
driving.  This is a
breakthrough racing game
running on iPhone 7 and 7 Plus.
Pro apps benefit as well.
This is Adobe Lightroom.  Adobe
Lightroom running on A10 Fusion
delivers 90% of the features
for raw editing of the desktop
version.  I mean, that's
incredible.  Adobe Lightroom on
a phone in your pocket doing
RAW editing.  It's simply
incredible.
We want to give you one
example of a game running live
on the A10 Fusion to show you
what it's capable of, so I am
very excited to bring up
Heather Price, Co-Founder of
This Game Studio.  Heather?
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; HEATHER PRICE: Thanks, P
Phil.
As mobile game developers, we
could not be more excited about
the horse power of the iPhone
7.  It's allowing us to create
cinematic gameplay experiences
that were simply not possible
before.  This is our new title,
Oz: Broken Kingdom, an ac
action-packed role playing
game.  Now, this isn't the Oz
you know.  A great darkness has
overtaken this once peaceful
land.  Here we are on the
bridge to the witch's castle
battling a scarecrow, who in
our version of the Oz is very
powerful.  We are able to do
things visually on the iPhone 7
that were simply not possible
before.  Note the real-time
reflections, weather effects,
all stunning and expensive from
a CPU standpoint but running
flawlessly on the iPhone 7.
And when Scott casts an
earthquake, you will see we
even have been able to add some
really cool environmental
destruction.
Okay, Scott, let's finish this
monkey captain off.
The witch has a ton of
reinforcements.  With the power
of Metal and the A10 chip, we
are able to render over 400 f
flying monkeys all at a
flawless, flawless frame rate.
(Applause)
One of the features we are
truly excited about is the wide
color display.  It is allowing
us to create extremely stunning
visual effects.  Now, although
it looks pretty good on this
screen, you really have to see
it on the iPhone 7 to see how
beautiful the game looks.
During the epic moments, the
haptic feedback is allowing us
to actually feel big hits, and
the stereo sound is pulling us
even further into the
environment, all leading to an
even more visceral connection
with our gameplay.
All right, Scott, let's cast a
tornado and knock her back.
Okay, I think it's time to
finish her off with Arcane N
Nova, one of Scarecrow's most
powerful abilities.
Join us in the epic journey to
cast back the darkness when Oz:
Broken Kingdom launches in the
App Store with iPhone 7.  Thank
you.
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; PHIL SCHILLER: Nothing
proves performance like 400 f
flying monkeys.
(Laughter)
Well, our A10 chip delivers
performance and incredible
efficiency.  So here's the
battery life numbers on iPhone
7 and 7 Plus.  Great battery
life numbers across the board.
Wi-fi browsing, 14 and 15 ho
hours.  LTE browsing, 12 and 13
hours.  Most importantly, our
customers are going to be so
excited to learn that the
iPhone 7 and 7 Plus are the
longest battery life ever in an
iPhone.
(Applause)
And here's another way to
think about battery life.  If
you are upgrading from an
iPhone 6s to an iPhone 7, on
average you can expect to get
about two more hours into your
day on your battery life.
That's a meaningful difference.
That's on average, some
customers many more than that.
And if you are coming from an
iPhone 6s Plus, which already
had great battery life, you
will find an iPhone 7 Plus
delivers at least an hour more
battery life on average to, and
for some customers, again, much
more than that.  So real
battery life difference you can
feel throughout every single
day.
So here is iPhone 7.  It is
packed with unbelievable
technologies, the 12 megapixel
technology, the large 4en
7-inch Retina HD display with
wide color gamut, optical image
stabilization, a 7-megapixel
FaceTime HD camera.  Our new
Home button that's solid state
and pressure sensitive.  It's
water and dust resistant, IP67.
Stereo speakers delivering
twice the audio volume.
Incredibly fast A10 Fusion
chip.  Faster wireless as well,
more bands and LTE, up to 450
megabits per second.  The
longest battery life ever in an
iPhone, and all running ois 10.
iOS X.  This is an incredible
iPhone.
After that, iPhone 7 Plus,
which is everything iPhone 7
has plus a longer battery life,
plus a larger display, and that
dual camera that provides zoom
and depth of field.
All of our iPhones are made in
the most environmentally
friendly manner as possible.
They are highly recyclable, and
without these harmful mate
materials.
iPhone 7 is the best phone
we've ever made, and we've got
a short video to sum it up for
you.
&gt;&gt; GREG JOSWIAK: This is
iPhone 7.  It makes all the
things you do with your iPhone
better, faster, and more
powerful.  Two new finishes,
black and jet black, highlight
its seamless design.  A new
camera captures shots you never
could before.  That's because
its larger f/1.8 aperture, new
sensor, and 6-element lens
enable brighter, more detailed
photos and videos.  And optical
image stabilization allows for
a longer exposure, so you get
even better images in low li
light.
The Apple design image signal
processor analyzes every shot
to automatically deliver the
very best results, and the q
quad-LED True Tone flash
illuminates brighter and
farther.  iPhone 7 Plus also
features a telephoto camera.
The two cameras operate as one,
giving you two times optical
zoom and high-quality imagery
when you zoom even farther.
The new Retina HD display,
with a cinema standard wide
color gamut is the best and
brightest ever on an iPhone.
It's also the first iPhone
with a stereo speaker system,
delivering a powerful, im
immersive audio experience.
The enclosure has been
entirely reengineered to make
this the first water resistant
iPhone.  It's driven by the A10
Fusion chip, the most powerful
chip ever in a smartphone.
High performance and high
efficiency cores let you do the
majority of your tasks at a
fraction of the power, giving
you the longest battery life of
any iPhone.
iPhone 7 makes the things you
do most even better.  It's the
best iPhone we've ever made.
(Applause)
&gt;&gt; PHIL SCHILLER: There's a
complete line of accessories,
all-new Apple designed
accessories for iPhone 7 and 7
Plus, new cases, new battery
cases, new charging docks, and
of course, the incredible new
AirPods.
So, what will iPhone 7 cost?
We are really excited to tell
you that iPhone 7 costs the
same as the iPhone 6s that it
replaces, just $649.  And, it
comes in silver, gold, rose
gold, black, and the new jet
black.  In these configurations
-- no, not these -- we've
doubled all the storage
configurations, so now it's 32
gigabytes, 128 gigabytes, and
256 gigabytes.  And jet black
specifically comes on 128 and
256 gig sizes.
iPhone 7 Plus starts at $769.
It also comes in 32 gigabytes,
128 gigabytes, and 256
gigabytes, and again, jet black
specifically on 128 and 256
gigabytes.
So now, this is our new iPhone
lineup.  It starts with iPhone
SE.  We move the 6 and 6s down
to the middle of the line.  And
at the top of the line, the now
iPhone 7 and 7 Plus.  We are
going to keep two
configurations of the 6s and
6s Plus around.  We are going
to do something we haven't done
before, upgrade the storage in
those as well to 32 gigs and
128 gigabytes.
(Applause)
We think customers at that
price range are going to really
appreciate that.
Now, we know many of our
customers purchase their phones
today on installment plans, so
here's the pricing with a
typical 24-month U.S. carrier
installment plan.  iPhone SE
starts at just $17 a month,
iPhone 7 at $27 a month.
Last year we introduced you to
a new program from our Apple
Apple Stores here in the U.S.
It's called the iPhone Upgrade
Program.  It's a great way to
get your iPhone new every year,
an unlocked phone with
AppleCare at an affordable
price.  I want to make a sh
shout-out first of all to
everybody who bought this
program last year because you
are becoming eligible this year
to get your new iPhone.  For
everyone else when you are
thinking about getting an
iPhone this year, realizing the
opportunity these people have
taken advantage of, you may
want to consider the same thing
so you can get a new iPhone
every single year.  We are
expanding the program to not
only the U.S., but also the UK
and China as well.
(Applause)
So, when can you order the new
iPhone 7 or 7 Plus?  Orders
start this Friday on September
9.  They will start shipping
one week later on September 16.
The team is working hard to
get it to as many customers
around the world as possible.
On September 16 we are going to
begin with this list of 28
geographies.  I hope you find
your favorite country there.
And one week later, 30 more.
So again, the team is working
very hard to bring these out
quickly around the world.
iOS 10 becomes available on
September 13.  I know we are
all going to be upgrading to
that as well.
And last, the new AirPods will
ship in late October and priced
at just $159.
So that's our news on iPhone.
Thank you.
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Thanks, Phil.
What a morning!  I hope that
you can get a sense from all
the details that we've shared,
the level of care that we put
into the products.  This is
what we love to do.
You've seen some incredible
products -- iPhone 7, the most
advanced iPhone ever.  It makes
all the things you do so much
better.
AirPods, helping usher in the
future of wireless audio,
providing effortless and
magical listening experience.
And the new Apple Watch Series
2, built-in GPS, incredible
water resistance, and a
powerful dual-core performance.
It's the ultimate device for a
healthy life.
Now, I'd like to take a moment
and recognize everyone from
Apple that worked so hard to
bring these products to market.
Please stand up.
(Applause)
It is an inspiration and a
privilege to have the
opportunity to work with all of
you.
You know, the Bill Graham
Auditorium is a legendary music
venue.  Music is at the core of
our DNA.  It deeply inspires
and moves us.  So stay right
where you are because today we
are honored to have an amazing
artist join us.  She is not
only a remarkable and talented
singer, but she's an incredible
songwriter, writing for both
herself and for many other
artists.  She's been headlining
the biggest music festivals all
over the world, and she is
currently topping the charts,
holding number one on AirPlay.
Her new song and video
premiered on Apple Music
earlier this week, and she is
here to perform it live for the
very first time.  Please join
me in welcoming Sia!
(Cheers and applause)
&gt;&gt; TIM COOK: Ladies and
gentlemen, Sia!
(Cheers and applause)
You guys are wonderful, so
wonderful.
Members of the press, there is
an unbelievable hands-on area
to your right.  Please check it
out and get your hands on these
products.  Thank you!